DRASHTEE PARMAR

(678) 467-4208 | drashteeparmar@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/drashteeparmar/

SUMMARY

An experienced Software Engineer with a demonstrated background in designing and implementing software systems and applications. A keen ability to work with developers to produce intellectual property that meets design schedules and customer functional and quality requirements. Experienced with the front-end application design as well as back-end verification and validation. Developed code in line with Agile and Test-Driven Development Methodologies.

KEY STRENGTHS

•	SDLC
---	------

- SDM
- Wireframe
- Problem solving

- Creativity
- Teamwork
- Communication
- Agile methodology

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Java
- HTML5
- CSS
- Java Script
- Node jQuery
- MongoDB

- Oracle Database
- Spring Booth
- Splunk JIRA
- Kafka
- Bootstrap
- GraphQL

- **Lucid Chart** Restful API
- GitHub
- Postman
- Swagger
- **Express** Heroku
- - - MySQL

AWS

VS Code

MS Office Suite

IntelliJ

React

Figma

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Associate Application Developer

ADP, Alpharetta GA

2019 -2021

- Initialized projects using AWS, Spring Boot Micro API Services.
- Developed code with Agile and Test-Driven Development Methodologies.
- Worked with Kafka, ICP, RESTful API, Swagger, Splunk.
- Attained and collaborate on stand-up calls for status updates and raise an issue if any
- Discuss and propose a solution that better fits enterprise architect, lead developer, and design needs by brainstorming, planning, developing, and contributing solutions to complex design work and develop user stories.
- Oversaw technical support and troubleshooting for client-facing issues.

Global Product and Technology Development Intern

ADP, Alpharetta GA

2018 -2018

- Led debugging various front-end and back-end applications at functional, design, and programming levels.
- Participated actively in Scrum meetings and manage Rally and JIRA Boards for keeping track of activities.

Quality Assurance 2012 -2018

Philips Respironics, Kennesaw GA

- Tested oxygen and medical devices to ensure operational functionality by monitoring all stages of the process to ensure a high-quality product.
- Trained employees to successfully maintain quality and compliance standards.

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

Java Programmer Certification

SWAGGA Certificate for service learning

COMMUNITY INVOLVEMENT

Developers Student Club

Society of Women Engineers

Women in Technology

EDUCATION

Georgia Institute of Technology, Master of Science in Computer Science **Georgia Institute of Technology,** Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp Kennesaw State University, Bachelor of Science in Software Engineering Chattahoochee Technical College, Associate of Science in Computer Programming **Currently Pursuing Currently Pursuing** May 2019 May 2016